<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" name="Project Name" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan"
	xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<release projectid="tools.ajdt" version="1.6" />
	<introduction>
		<html:div>
			<html:p>
				As of version 2.0.0, AJDT is using a new versioning scheme, which is
				more aligned with traditional notions of major/minor/maintenance
				releases. A maintenance release implies trivial functionality and
				bug fixes have been added. A minor release implies some
				significant functionality and features introduced, but API is largely backwards
				compatible. A major release implies
				breaking API changes.

				AJDT major versions match up with Eclipse versions. The current Eclipse
				version is 3.4, which matches to AJDT 1.6.
				Eclipse 3.3 matches AJDT 1.5, and Eclipse 3.5 will match AJDT 1.7.
				The AJDT project releases service refreshes to that major version every
				few months. During 2008 there
				have been 1.5.2, 1.5.3 (the last scheduled version targeting Eclipse
				3.3), 1.6.0 (the first version targeting Eclipse 3.4),
				1.6.1, and 1.6.2. In 2009, there has been 1.6.3, 1.6.4, and 2.0.0
				releases.
</html:p>
			<html:p>
				There are two streams for the 2.0.0 release: one targeting Eclipse
				3.4 (this stream uses a version qualifier starting with
				<html:em>_e34x</html:em>
				) and one targeting Eclipse 3.5 (using a version qualifier starting
				with
				<html:em>_e35x</html:em>
				.
			</html:p>
			<html:p>
				We tend to release on an approximately 3 month schedule, excluding the
				recent exception of AJDT 1.6.3. Most
				of these releases will be maintenance releases, with perhaps one minor
				release a year. There are no
				plans for anothe major release in the near future.
</html:p>
			<html:p>
				AJDT always maintains that HEAD will build clean and pass all the tests
				we have (currently over 500).
				This is almost 200 more tests than six months ago. The test suite is now
				in fairly solid shape and tests
				all major parts of AJDT. This means the development builds created from
				HEAD after every commit are typically
				at least as good as the previous build.
</html:p>
		</html:div>
	</introduction>
	<release_deliverables>
		<html:div>
			<html:p>
				AJDT releases are available from project update sites. There are
				different sites for each
				minor release see
				<html:a href="http://eclipse.org/ajdt/downloads">the project download page</html:a>
				for a list of the update sites. Also available are zip files that
				contain all of the project plugins and
				are meant to be installed in the eclipse installation's
				<html:em>dropins</html:em>
				folder.
			</html:p>
			<html:p>
				AJDT includes 6 plugins from two other EPL Eclipse.org projects:
				<html:ul>
					<html:li>
						The
						<html:a
							href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.php?projectid=tools.aspectj">AspectJ project</html:a>
						contributes three plugins.
						These plugins are
						<html:em>org.aspectj.runtime</html:em>
						, which contains the AspectJ runtime,
						<html:em>org.aspectj.ajde</html:em>
						, which contains AspectJ support for integrating with a
						development environment,
						and
						<html:em>org.aspectj.weaver</html:em>
						, which contains the AspectJ weaver and compiler.
					</html:li>

					<html:li>
						The
						<html:a
							href="http://www.eclipse.org/equinox/incubator/aspects/index.php">Equinox Aspects project</html:a>
						, part of the Eqinox Incubator also contributes three plugins.
						These are
						<html:em>org.eclipse.equinox.weaving.aspectj
						</html:em>
						, which contains the equinox weaving service,
						<html:em>org.eclipse.equinox.weaving.hook
						</html:em>
						, which contains the OSGi framework extension for the weaving
						service to plug in, and
						<html:em>org.eclipse.equinox.weaving.source
						</html:em>
						, which contains Equinox Aspects source code.
					</html:li>
				</html:ul>
			</html:p>
		</html:div>
	</release_deliverables>
	<release_milestones>
		<preamble>
		</preamble>
		<milestone date="06/30/2009" milestone="2.0.0">
			<html:div>First release that targets both Eclipse 3.4 stream and
				Eclipse 3.5 stream.</html:div>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="09/20/2009" milestone="2.0.1">
			<html:div>Service refresh of AJDT 2.0. Streams for both 3.4
				and 3.5 will be released.</html:div>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="12/20/2009" milestone="2.0.2">
			<html:div>Service refresh of AJDT 2.0. Streams for both 3.4
				and 3.5 will be released.</html:div>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="03/20/2010" milestone="2.0.3">
			<html:div>Service refresh of AJDT 2.0. Only 3.5 stream will be
				released unless there is
				significant community desiire for a 3.4 stream.</html:div>
		</milestone>
		<postamble>
		</postamble>
	</release_milestones>
	<target_environments>
		<html:div>AJDT 2.0.0_e34x requires Eclipse 3.4 and AJDT 2.0.0_e35x
			will requires Eclipse 3.5.
			As such, AJDT has the same JRE requirements as Eclipse.</html:div>
		<internationalization>
			<html:div>English language bundles are available for many AJDT
				messages, but they have not been translated.
          </html:div>
		</internationalization>
	</target_environments>
	<compatibility_with_previous_releases>
		<html:div>
			Each version of AJDT will only run on the version of Eclipse that is
			specified in its qualifier (e.g.,
			<html:em>_e34x</html:em>
			or
			<html:em>_e35x. However, we will maintain API compatibility
				across minor releases and streams.</html:em>
			.
		</html:div>
	</compatibility_with_previous_releases>
	<themes_and_priorities>
		<preamble>
			<html:div>Our current focus is three-fold: Intertype declaration
				support, IDE support for load-time weaving, and crosscutting model
				support across projects and binaries. These themes are generated
				from user requests in the community. As such, we want
				to maintain flexibility and put effort into new themes if they are
				coherently generated from the community.
			</html:div>
		</preamble>
		<theme name="Intertype Declaration support (ITD)">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Third party projects such as <html:a href="http://sringsource.org/roo">ROO</html:a>	are pushing the
					limits of ITD functionality both in the compiler and the editor.  Since this is a highly visible project
					with many potential users, we would like to encourage its adoption by facilitating the ITD editor support 
					that it requires.  This include facility for ITD-aware content assist, reconciling, refactoring, searching 
					and navigation.  
				</html:p>
			</description>
			<committed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/qkated">
			</committed>
			<proposed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/r6y4vb">
			</proposed>
		</theme>
		<theme name="IDE support for Load Time Weaving (LTW)">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Currently, aspects applied to a project through LTW are not visible in the
					editor in the standard ways that compile time aspects are. These
					include
					gutter annotations and entries in the crosscutting view. Because there is
					no editing support, using LTW can be time consuming and
					error-prone. We will
					explore ways to gather and display LTW information to the programmer while
					editing.
        </html:p>
			</description>
			<committed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/p6h8wo">
			</committed>
			<proposed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/odh8a8">
			</proposed>
		</theme>
		<theme
			name="Crosscutting model support across projects and binaries (model)">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Provide support for navigation and across the aspect path and in path.
				</html:p>
			</description>
			<committed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/qh8mep">
			</committed>
			<proposed
				bugzilla="http://tinyurl.com/pzlzge">
			</proposed>
		</theme>
	</themes_and_priorities>
</plan>